太空叉打算在2022年发射BFR前往火星
In the year 2022, SpaceX aims to send their BFR rocket on its first trip to Mars
BFR高106米，直径9米，比猎鹰九号和重型猎鹰高到不知哪里去了
Standing at 106m tall and 9m in diameter, the BFR will dwarf the Falcon 9 and Falcon Heavy rockets
于是问题来了，BFR这么大该怎么运？
This raises the question, how will SpaceX transport the BFR?
本期视频我们将罗列出太空叉运输BFR穿越美国的可选方案
In this video we are going to look at the different methods SpaceX might choose to transport
the enormous BFR rocket across the country
我们还将回望人类航天的过去
We are also going to look back to the early days of spaceflight
详情见av14026384
了解下当年土星五号是如何运输的
and compare how the Saturn V was transported
要想知道这么大火箭有多难运
In order to understand how challenging the BFR’s journey will be
我们得先知道这东西从哪来、到哪去
we have to know where it’s coming from and where it’s going
目前情报来看，BFR将在洛杉矶圣佩德罗港口一工厂制造
The BFR looks set to be manufactured at a factory in the Port of San Pedro, Los Angeles
虽然BFR的发射场还没确定下来
The intended launch site for the BFR is not yet decided, however
但首飞应该还是在肯尼迪航天中心的LC39A
initial launches are expected to take place from Pad 39A at the Kennedy Space Center
静态点火也很有可能在得克萨斯州的Boca Chica
Static fire tests will most likely take place in Boca Chica, Texas
太空叉在当地正在建一座新设施
where SpaceX are building a brand new facility
详情见av22149359
在之前的视频中，我们讲过猎鹰九号是如何从加州跋山涉水到佛州的
In a previous Primal Space video, we looked at the long journey the Falcon 9 travels from California to Florida
猎鹰九号设计的时候，其直径限制在3.7米
When the Falcon 9 was designed, the diameter of the rocket was limited to 3.7m
来保证一路上可以顺利钻过所有立交桥
in order to fit under every overpass it would come across on it’s journey
而BFR相比猎鹰九号，不但更♂粗，还更♂长了
Not only will the BFR be much wider than the Falcon 9, it will also be much longer
使得运输上的统筹更加困难
making the logistics even more difficult
BFR助推段58米，入轨的飞船部分48米
With the booster section being 58m long and the spacecraft section being 48m long
公路、铁路、空运它都不可能
it would be impossible to transport the BFR by road, air OR rail
从加州到佛州的唯一的办法就是走海路
The only possible way the BFR will be able get from California to Florida is by sea
而新BFR工厂刚好在洛圣都的港口
With the new BFR factory being located in the port of Los Angeles
因此BFR的各段可以轻松装船然后运到东海岸
the BFR sections can easily be loaded onto a barge which will take them to the east coast
当各部件装船后，它们航行南下
Once the parts are on the barge, they will then travel south
然后穿越巴拿马运河，再北上回到卡角
and make their way through the Panama canal and back up to Cape Canaveral
在那它们将被组装、发射
where they will be assembled and launched
尽管把造BFR的工厂放在离发射场“一国之隔”的地方不太好
While it may seem impractical to have the BFR factory on the opposite side of the country from the launch site
把BFR工厂放在加州却是很明智的选择
building the new BFR factory in California is actually very sensible
对于太空叉来说，把基地继续留在加州是很合理的
It makes much more sense for SpaceX to keep their base in California
因为他们好多员工和资源都在西海岸这边
where all of their employees and resources are located
而不用公司整个搬家去国家另一头
than to move everything to a factory on the other side of the country
详情见av14026384
回到阿波罗的时代，土星五号运输的方式和刚刚说的非常相似
Back in the Apollo days, the Saturn V used a very similar method of transport
二级部分同样是从加州南下穿过巴拿马运河再北上到卡角
with the second stage following the same journey from California to Cape Canaveral passing through the Panama canal
尽管BFR看上去旅途和土星五号很像
Although it looks like the BFR will follow a similar journey to the Saturn V
但其实会更加简单
it will be a much simpler journey overall
因为BFR的零件比土星五号少多了，而且来源集中在同一处
since the BFR has less parts and all of those parts are coming from the same place
而土星五号，是由好几个州分开制造的
The Saturn V on the other hand, was built in a number of different States
于是这一大堆零件运输上的协调简直是噩梦难度
making it a logistical nightmare to transport it to the launch pad
虽然BFR很可能是用两条拖船走水路运输
Although the BFR will most likely be shipped as two large sections
但它的猛禽发动机应该还会走陆路去德州的McGregor测试中心进行测试
the Raptor engines will still have to be transported by road to the testing facility in McGregor, Texas
然后再运回到加州与BFR连接
and then back to California to be attached to the BFR booster
一些小部件比如三角翼，是有可能走陆路运输的
It’s also possible that smaller parts like the Delta wing could be shipped by road
和其他零件在卡角会合并组装
and assembled once it reaches Cape Canaveral
所以这么看来，太空叉对BFR这个大饼付出的努力
So as we look forward to seeing the progress SpaceX make to their BFR
我们应该理解他们为了运输这艘带人类去火星的载具所付出的努力
we can appreciate the enormous effort that’s needed to transport the machines that will take us to Mars
如果你喜欢这个视频，记得关注YouTuber “Primal Space”，Patreon链接见下
If you enjoyed this video and would like to contribute to Primal Space, please visit Patreon.com/PrimalSpace
如果想了解更多关于火箭运输的姿势
If you would like to learn more about how rockets are transported
详情见av22149359
欢迎看我之前做的运输猎鹰九号的视频
check out my video on how SpaceX transport the Falcon 9
最后记得关注点赞分享收藏投币，带你提高致己关于太空的姿势水平
and make sure you’re subscribed so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space
字幕翻译给虫，我们下期见
Thank you very much for watching and I’ll see you in the next video